THIEN NGUYEN

Phone/ Whatsapp: (+84) 775188017 | Email: ngthien2911@gmail.com | Skype: ngthien2911

SUMMARY

Professional service-oriented person with more than 5 years of experience in Hospitality and Tourism Industry. Strong ability on applying technology to maximize productivity at work, familiar with using several well-developed tools and systems of multinational companies such as Traveloka, TUI Group. Able to work effectively both with a team and individually without supervision. Have experience working with front/back-end of the product. Have experience using HTML5, CSS3, ReactJs, Redux, Postman and SQL

SKILLS & EXPERTISE

Customer Service • Interpersonal & Communication Skill • Web development • Problem Solving • Self-management • Tech-savvy

EXPERIENCES

May 2021 - Present: Front-end developer

- Using HTML5, CSS3 for web development.
- Using ReactJs and Redux to develope sites calling APIs.
- Creating basic apps with JS and React
- Get to know Git, GitLab and pratice handling conflicts on Git
- Github: https://github.com/ngthien2911
- Project: https://ngthien2911ecommerce.netlify.app/

TUI GROUP | One of the world's largest leisure, travel and tourism company in the world

Operation Manager October 2018 – Present

- Managed destination service operation in Phu Quoc including: finance activities, partnership development, tours operation, logistic management, quests satisfaction,...
- Provided technical support and administrative support for the Phu Quoc office.
- Served as the main contact point to work with local authorities at the airport and on the island.
- Trained to be key account of the Vietnam Branch on using Asterix (TUI Group's standardised fully integrated system for all countries)

TRAVELOKA | Technology company aims to revolutionize human mobility with technology

Customer Support Representative April 2018 – October 2018

- Acted as a second-tier point of escalation from the customer service team thus expected to solve cases related with ticketing, payment processing, issuance, amendment, relocation, instruction.
- Served as liaison between customer service with Payment and Ticketing Team, and thus has to formulate requests on required action and escalation needs to the right team.
- Managed customer cases through case management and customer database applications within allowable solving time (1 to 24 hours case by case).

VESPA ADVENTURES & ONETRIP | Travel agencies focusing on international guests

Freelancer Tour Guide February 2017 - April 2018

Led different local experience trips in Saigon for international guests such as: Saigon after dark, City tours, ...

ONETRIP & CHRISTINAS VIETNAM COMPANY LIMITED | Tech driven fully-integrated travel experience company Tour leader & Host July 2015 – February 2017

- Participated in Onetrip tour operations, including designing new tours, lead tours of Onetrip Saigon & Hoian, and enhanced quests' experience on tours.
- Participated in host operations of Christina's in Saigon & Hoian including: check-in, check-out guests, manage housekeeping team, solve in-house technical issues, handle guests crises.

EDUCATION & AWARD

HO CHI MINH CITY UNIVERSITY OF INDUSTRY | HCMC, VIETNAM Bachelor of Environmental Science of engineering and management

INTERNATIONAL TOUR GUIDE LICENSE

EXTRA ACTIVITIES

IVC - INTERNATIONAL VOLUNTEER CLUB Volunteer